<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Works on Michael Buchel</title><link>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/</link><description>Recent content in Works on Michael Buchel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:14:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mbuchel.github.io/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MR Clutch</title><link>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/mr-clutch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:14:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/mr-clutch/</guid><description>Purpose of Work: This was primarily a research position, where I was supposed to create the electronic component of the MR Clutch being developed by Dr. Kermani at Western University.
Details of Work: During this employement, I have worked on the following areas:
Build Systems STM Development CAN Protocol KiCad Real Time Systems On top of this I also developed a GUI application, explanation here.
Lessons Learned: How MR Clutches work, as well as some FreeRTOS specifics/designing proper free real time operating systems for embedded devices.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom Picking</title><link>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/mushroom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 14:54:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/mushroom/</guid><description>Purpose of Work: As we enter the Digital Revolution it only makes sense that our low level jobs are replaced by automated machine which in turn can handle menial tasks such as picking mushrooms. This was done under the supervision of Dr. Kermani at Western University, as research for the company Mycionics Incorporated.
Details of Work: I performed quite a few tasks for this work, from computer vision algorithm development, to mobile app/server development.</description></item><item><title>WearME Brace</title><link>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/wearme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 14:22:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mbuchel.github.io/work/wearme/</guid><description>Purpose of Work: This work was designed in order to help individuals suffering from musculoskeletal disorders such as parkinsons in rehabilitation and assisting their day to day lives. This technology shows a lot of potential in the future of human wearable devices. The work was performed under the supervision of Dr. Trejos at Western University.
Details of Work: The work was split into 5 components, 4 of which I have worked on directly, with the last component work was done indirectly.</description></item></channel></rss>